<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects |</title><link>https://example.com/project/</link><atom:link href="https://example.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://example.com/project/</link></image><item><title>BigBIO: Biomedical Datasets</title><link>https://example.com/project/bigbio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/bigbio/</guid><description>&lt;p>BigBIO (BigScience Biomedical) is an open library of biomedical dataloaders built using Huggingface&amp;rsquo;s (🤗) datasets library for data-centric machine learning. Our goals include&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lightweight, programmatic access to biomedical datasets at scale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Promote reproducibility in data processing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better documentation for dataset provenance, licensing, and other key attributes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easier generation of meta-datasets (e.g., prompting, masssive MTL)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Currently BigBIO provides support for&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>more than 120 biomedical datasets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 languages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Harmonized dataset schemas by task type&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Metadata on licensing, coarse/fine-grained task types, domain, and more!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>LinkExplorer</title><link>https://example.com/project/linkexplorer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/linkexplorer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The LinkExplorer is a web-based tool for exploring nodes and relations of link prediction benchmark datasets and explanations of predictions done with the rule-based approach SAFRAN. A running instance of this tool can be found at:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://explore.ai-strategies.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://explore.ai-strategies.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Included are three biomedical knowledge bases:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>OpenBioLink&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hetionet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pheknowlator&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>and two general-domain benchmarks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>YAGO3-10&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WN18RR&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>SAFRAN</title><link>https://example.com/project/safran/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/safran/</guid><description>&lt;p>SAFRAN (Scalable and fast non-redundant rule application) is a framework for fast inference of groundings and aggregation of predictions of logical rules in the context of knowledge graph completion/link prediction. It uses rules learned by AnyBURL (Anytime Bottom Up Rule Learning), a highly-efficient approach for learning logical rules from knowledge graphs. AnyBURL [Meilicke et al., 2019, 2020] is currently one of the best performing symbolic rule learners and demonstrated results competitive with embedding methods on link prediction benchmarks such as FB15k-237. However, the application of rules generated by Any-BURL is currently limited by functional redundancies, making it difficult to meaningfully aggregate predictions made by different rules and thereby limiting predictive performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We introduce the high-performance rule application framework SAFRAN (’Scalable And fast non-redundant rule application’) that employs a novel aggregation approach. We propose an algorithm called Non-redundant Noisy-OR that detects redundant rules prior to aggregation, mitigating their negative effects and improving predictive performance. This algorithm for aggregating predictions is not necessarily restricted to rules learned by AnyBURL and could also be applied to other rule-based system&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>safety-code</title><link>https://example.com/project/safetycode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/safetycode/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s make data on essential pharmacogenes available for every patient everywhere!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The availability of pharmacogenomic data of individual patients can significantly improve physicians' prescribing behaviour and lead to a &lt;strong>reduced incidence of adverse drug events&lt;/strong> and an &lt;strong>improvement of effectiveness of treatment&lt;/strong>. Unfortunately, &lt;strong>major barriers&lt;/strong> to the wide-spread implementation of pharmacogenomics in clinical practice remain:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Significant financial cost and turnaround time as well as limited availability of indication-specific pharmacogenomic tests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Difficulties in the storage, exchange, and interpretation of pharmacogenetic data. In particular, interoperable electronic health record systems that are capable of storing structured genetic test results and transmitting those results to other care providers are needed; unfortunately, this type of infrastructure is not available in most parts of the world.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A lack of easily accessible computer-based clinical decision support systems that can assist clinicians with the interpretation of pharmacogenetic data – a vital component to the use of these data at the point of care.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A possible solution: The Medication Safety Code&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make patient genotype data on essential pharmacogenes globally available for routine medical care, technologically-simple and intuitive systems are required in order to minimize the need for specialized infrastructure, software, and knowledge. The Medication Safety Code initiative is an effort to improve the ability of clinicians and patients to share pharmacogenetic data and to use it at the point of care. This system consists of two major components:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>The Medication Safety Code (MSC), a standardized two-dimensional (2D) barcode&lt;/strong> that captures data about genetic variants in essential pharmacogenes for an individual patient. The 2D barcode is based on the Quick Response (QR) code standard, which has become widely popular in recent years because it can be decoded quickly and reliably, has relatively high information density and can encode hyperlinks to pages on the World Wide Web. In addition, the MSC data can also be embedded in electronic health records.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A curated knowledge base&lt;/strong> that contains information about essential pharmacogenes, including haplotype definitions, phenotype translations and clinical guidelines. This knowledge base is used to automatically interpret the genetic data that is encoded within the 2D barcodes. The knowledge base leverages semantic technologies and ontologies to ensure a high degree of interoperability with other systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>OpenBioLink</title><link>https://example.com/project/openbiolink/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/openbiolink/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenBioLink is a resource and evaluation framework for evaluating link prediction models on heterogeneous biomedical graph data. It contains benchmark datasets as well as tools for creating custom benchmarks and evaluating models.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The OpenBioLink benchmark aims to meet the following criteria:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Openly available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Large-scale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wide coverage of current biomedical knowledge and entity types&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Standardized, balanced train-test split&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open-source code for benchmark dataset generation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open-source code for evaluation (independent of model)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrating and differentiating multiple types of biological entities and relations (i.e., formalized as a heterogeneous graph)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minimized information leakage between train and test sets (e.g., avoid inclusion of trivially inferable relations in the test set)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coverage of true negative relations, where available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Differentiating high-quality data from noisy, low-quality data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Differentiating benchmarks for directed and undirected graphs in order to be applicable to a wide variety of link prediction methods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clearly defined release cycle with versions of the benchmark and public leaderboard&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The OpenBioLink2020 Dataset is a highly challenging benchmark dataset containing over 5 million positive and negative edges. The test set does not contain trivially predictable, inverse edges from the training set and does contain all different edge types, to provide a more realistic edge prediction scenario.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="datasets-summary">Datasets summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Dataset&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Train&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Test&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Valid&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Entities&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Relations&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>directed, high quality&lt;/td>
&lt;td>8.503.580&lt;/td>
&lt;td>401.901&lt;/td>
&lt;td>397.066&lt;/td>
&lt;td>184.732&lt;/td>
&lt;td>28&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>undirected, high quality&lt;/td>
&lt;td>7.559.921&lt;/td>
&lt;td>372.877&lt;/td>
&lt;td>357.297&lt;/td>
&lt;td>184.722&lt;/td>
&lt;td>28&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>directed, no quality cutoff&lt;/td>
&lt;td>51.636.927&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2.079.139&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2.474.921&lt;/td>
&lt;td>486.998&lt;/td>
&lt;td>32&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>undirected, no quality cutoff&lt;/td>
&lt;td>41.383.093&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2.010.662&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1.932.436&lt;/td>
&lt;td>486.998&lt;/td>
&lt;td>32&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="baseline-results">Baseline results&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Model&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">MRR&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">h@1&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:center">h@10&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Latent&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">RESCAL&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;strong>.320&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.212&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.544&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">TransE&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.280&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.175&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.500&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">DistMult&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.300&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.193&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.521&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">ComplEx&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.319&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.211&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;strong>.547&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">ConvE&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.288&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.186&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.510&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">RotatE&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.286&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.180&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.511&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Interpretable&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">AnyBURL (Maximum)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.277&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.192&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.457&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">AnyBURL (Noisy-OR)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.159&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.098&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">.295&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">SAFRAN*&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;u>.306&lt;/u>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;u>&lt;strong>.214&lt;/strong>&lt;/u>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:center">&lt;u>.501&lt;/u>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Results are from &lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2022.01.09.475537v2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(LinkExplorer: Predicting, explaining and exploring links in large biomedical knowledge graphs; Ott et al)&lt;/a>. Embedding approaches were trained using &lt;a href="https://github.com/uma-pi1/kge" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LibKGE&lt;/a>. Best hyperparameters after extensive hyperparameter search can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/biorxiv/early/2022/01/31/2022.01.09.475537/DC1/embed/media-1.pdf?download=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">supplementary material&lt;/a> of the before mentioned paper.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>